BRIAN **HARTONG**

Bridgewater, NJ · 908-581-5581

bhartong.jobs@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/brianhartong · brianhartong.com

Multi-faceted software developer who is an expert in C#, .Net Framework, and WinForms. A strong team player offering 9 years of experience in the software industry. Seeking the opportunity to provide outstanding clean code in a collaborative environment. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting.

SKILLS

- C#, C++, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, bootstrap, Ajax, PHP, LAMP, SQL
- .Net Framework 4.5+, WinForms
- Windows Services
- Experienced with Microsoft Add-ins
- Skilled in Java, Lua, Python
- Knowledgeable in Visual Studio
- Excellent command of Unity3D
- Competent in Adobe Photoshop

- Familiar with TCP/IP networking
- Ability to work well as a team member
- Strong leadership abilities
- Trained in object-oriented programming, game programming
- Exceptional ability to write cohesive and organized code
- Experienced with project management software

EXPERIENCE

OCTOBER 2018 - PRESENT

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, WORLD SOFTWARE CORPORATION

- Build and manage C# Microsoft Office integrations (Word, Excel, PowerPoint).
- Develop and sustain Microsoft Teams, TrueSign, Citrix ShareFile, and Citrix RightSignature integrations.
- Create and support Microsoft Outlook integration with company developed document management system (Worldox).
- Expand and maintain a C# email crawler application.

JUNE 2014 – APRIL 2018

LEAD SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AND TECHNICAL PROJECT MANAGER, ACTIVATE

- Developed 30 pharmaceutical emails in HTML5 that replicated client provided specifications and images flawlessly.
- Wrote C# applications in Unity3D architecture.
- Implemented Assembla with GIT for version control.
- Worked closely with clients to establish program specifications and system designs.
- Ensured bug reports were remedied, and all issues were handled in a timely manner.
- Designed and developed 2 to 3 software web applications per month.
- Designed and programmed a custom learning management system.
- Managed outsourced developers, both domestic and international.

SEPTEMBER 2012 – DECEMBER 2012

PROJECT LEAD AND SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, SCHOOL PROJECT

- Managed a small team to develop a shooter game using a NERF gun as a controller.
- Helped design and program a TCP/IP connection between controller and game.
- Managed design and code production.
- Managed contact between team members and group leads.
- Designed and programed AI robot system.
- Reported changes of game systems to robotic team.

SPETEMBER 2011 – MARCH 2012

LEAD PROGRAMMER, POLITICALLY INCORRECT GAMES

- Responsible for designing and planning code.
- Served as liaison between programmers and project head.
- Worked on the team of developers for Delirium.
- Assisted with conceptualization and design.
- Analyzed code performance and optimized code for speed.
- Managed bug fixes and problems.
- Responsible for game testing.

EDUCATION

EXPECTED GRADUATION 2023

BS COMPUTER SCIENCE, SOUTHERN NEW HAMPSHIRE UNIVERSITY

SEPTEMBER 2011 – FEBRUARY 2014

GAME PROGRAMMING, UNIVERSITY OF ADVANCING TECHNOLOGY

MAY 2010

AAS GAME DEVELOPMENT, RARITAN VALLEY COMMUNITY COLLEGE